<sc id="Hebreos-9">
<cm>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-1">
Now indeed even the first
<rb>
<t xml:lang="es"/><rf>TR adds «tabernacle»<t xml:lang="es"/></rf>
</rb>
 covenant had
ordinances of divine service, and an earthly sanctuary.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-2">
For there was a
tabernacle prepared. In the first part were the lampstand, the table, and the
show bread; which is called the Holy Place.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-3">
After the second veil was
the tabernacle which is called the Holy of Holies,
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-4">
having a golden altar
of incense, and the ark of the covenant overlaid on all sides with gold, in
which was a golden pot holding the manna, Aaron´s rod that budded, and the
tables of the covenant;
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-5">
and above it cherubim of glory overshadowing the
mercy seat, of which things we can´t now speak in detail.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-6">
Now these
things having been thus prepared, the priests go in continually into the
first tabernacle, accomplishing the services,
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-7">
but into the second the
high priest alone, once in the year, not without blood, which he offers for
himself, and for the errors of the people.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-8">
The Holy Spirit is indicating
this, that the way into the Holy Place wasn´t yet revealed while the first
tabernacle was still standing;
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-9">
which is a symbol of the present age,
where gifts and sacrifices are offered that are incapable, concerning the
conscience, of making the worshipper perfect;
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-10">
being only (with meats
and drinks and various washings) fleshly ordinances, imposed until a time of
reformation.

</sv></cm><cm>

<sv id="Hebreos-9-11">
But Christ having come as a high priest of the coming good things,
through the greater and more perfect tabernacle, not made with hands, that is
to say, not of this creation,
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-12">
nor yet through the blood of goats and
calves, but through his own blood, entered in once for all into the Holy
Place, having obtained eternal redemption.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-13">
For if the blood of goats
and bulls, and the ashes of a heifer sprinkling those who have been defiled,
sanctify to the cleanness of the flesh:
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-14">
how much more will the blood of
Christ, who through the eternal Spirit offered himself without blemish to
God, cleanse your conscience from dead works to serve the living God?

</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-15">
For this reason he is the mediator of a new covenant, since a death has
occurred for the redemption of the transgressions that were under the first
covenant, that those who have been called may receive the promise of the
eternal inheritance.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-16">
For where a last will and testament is, there must
of necessity be the death of him who made it.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-17">
For a will is in force
where there has been death, for it is never in force while he who made it
lives.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-18">
Therefore even the first covenant has not been dedicated without
blood.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-19">
For when every commandment had been spoken by Moses to all the
people according to the law, he took the blood of the calves and the goats,
with water and scarlet wool and hyssop, and sprinkled both the book itself
and all the people,
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-20">
saying, «This is the blood of the covenant which
God has commanded you.»

</sv></cm><cm>

<sv id="Hebreos-9-21">
Moreover he sprinkled the tabernacle and all the vessels of the
ministry in like manner with the blood.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-22">
According to the law, nearly
everything is cleansed with blood, and apart from shedding of blood there is
no remission.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-23">
It was necessary therefore that the copies of the things
in the heavens should be cleansed with these; but the heavenly things
themselves with better sacrifices than these.
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-24">
For Christ hasn´t entered
into holy places made with hands, which are representations of the true, but
into heaven itself, now to appear in the presence of God for us;
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-25">
nor
yet that he should offer himself often, as the high priest enters into the
holy place year by year with blood not his own,
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-26">
or else he must have
suffered often since the foundation of the world. But now once at the end of
the ages, he has been revealed to put away sin by the sacrifice of himself.

</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-27">
Inasmuch as it is appointed for men to die once, and after this,
judgment,
</sv>
<sv id="Hebreos-9-28">
so Christ also, having been once offered to bear the sins of
many, will appear a second time, without sin, to those who are eagerly
waiting for him for salvation.

<cl/>


</sv></cm></sc>
